<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>com.protonvpn.www</id>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
    <name>Proton VPN</name>
    <developer_name>Proton AG</developer_name>
    <summary>Trusted and easy-to-use VPN app for Linux</summary>
    <description>
        <p>NOTE: This release is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by Proton AG.</p>
        <p>Proton VPN is the world's only free VPN app that is safe to use and respects your
            privacy. Proton VPN is created by the CERN scientists behind Proton Mail - the world's
            largest encrypted email service. Our fast VPN offers secure, private and encrypted
            internet access with advanced security features. Proton VPN also unblocks access to
            popular websites and streaming platforms.</p>
        <p>Used by millions worldwide, Proton’s secure no-logs VPN offers 24/7 safe and private
            internet access, and does not record your browsing history, display ads, sell your data
            to third parties, or limit downloads.</p>
        <p>Free VPN features available to all users</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Unlimited data with no bandwidth or speed restrictions</li>
            <li>Strict no logs policy</li>
            <li>Bypass geo restrictions: smart protocol selection automatically overcomes VPN bans
                and unblocks censored sites and content</li>
            <li>Full disk encrypted servers protect your data</li>
            <li>Perfect forward secrecy: encrypted traffic cannot be captured and decrypted later</li>
            <li>DNS leak protection: we encrypt DNS queries to ensure that your browsing activity
                cannot be exposed through DNS leaks</li>
            <li>Always-on VPN/ kill switch offers protection against leaks caused by accidental
                disconnections</li>

        </ul>
        <p>Premium VPN features</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Access 2900+ high speed servers across 65+ countries worldwide</li>
            <li>Fast VPN: high speed servers with connections up to 10 Gbps</li>
            <li>VPN Accelerator: unique technology increases Proton VPN's speeds by up to 400% to
                give a faster browsing experience</li>
            <li>Unblock access to blocked or censored content</li>
            <li>Connect up to 10 devices to the VPN at the same time</li>
            <li>Ad blocker (NetShield): a DNS filtering feature that protects you from malware,
                blocks ads, and prevents website trackers from following you across the web</li>
            <li>Stream films, sports events, and videos on any streaming service (Netflix, Hulu,
                Amazon Prime Video, Disney+, BBC iplayer etc)</li>
            <li>File-sharing and P2P support</li>
            <li>Secure Core servers protect against network-based attacks with multi-hop VPN</li>
            <li>Tor over VPN provides automatic integration with the Tor anonymity network</li>
            <li>Split tunneling support allows you to select which apps go through the VPN tunnel</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Why choose Proton VPN?</p>
        <ul>
            <li>No-logs VPN: We do not keep any logs that can identify what you do online</li>
            <li>DNS and IPv6 leak protection: Our Linux app will never accidentally expose your real
                IP address</li>
            <li>Easy-to-use interface: The new Proton VPN Linux app has an intuitive graphical user
                interface that lets you quickly activate features and connect to servers</li>
            <li>P2P support: Share and download files using BitTorrent and other P2P protocols</li>
            <li>VPN Accelerator: Free and available to everyone who uses Proton VPN, our unique VPN
                Accelerator technology can improve speeds by over 400%</li>
            <li>Strong encryption: Our Linux app uses the OpenVPN protocol at its strongest
                encryption settings</li>
            <li>Based in Switzerland: Switzerland has some of the world's strongest data privacy
                laws</li>
            <li>Secure streaming: Unblock popular streaming services and watch your favorite shows</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Join the privacy revolution</p>
        <p>Your support is important as it allows us to continue our mission to bring online freedom
            to people around the globe. Get our private VPN free today and enjoy fast VPN
            connections and a secure internet, from anywhere.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>
                https://protonvpn.com/support/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/ubuntu-desktop.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <url type="homepage">https://protonvpn.com/</url>
    <url type="contact">https://protonvpn.com/support-form</url>
    <url type="help">https://protonvpn.com/support/linux-vpn-setup/</url>
    <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ProtonVPN/proton-vpn-gtk-app</url>

    <releases>
        <release version="4.1.0" date="2022-11-02" />
        <release version="4.0.0" date="2022-10-10" />
    </releases>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>
</component>